Today we're going to talk about how to diagnose an ailment of your fish.
Part of keeping a fish is making sure that we visually inspect them everyday.
When we feed them we want to make sure that they have a good appetite and that their fins are not torn, they're not in rough shape, they're not sitting at the bottom.
Once you've been keeping your fish for a while, you're going to know if they're acting different.
A common problem with fish is Ick which is tiny white spots over the entire fish itself.
A lot of ailments are caused by stress which can be water quality, temperature and fish stressing out other fish themselves.
One thing that I like to start with if there is a regular ailment going on is using a natural product.
We have MELAFIX and PEMEFIX. MELAFIX is an anti-bacterial and PEMEFIX is an anti-fungal. What I like to do is use both of them together because its not an exact science of exactly what's going on with the fish so if there is a bacterial problem, we can take care of fungus as well if that happens to be part of the issue as well.
Simply follow directions and it tells you exactly how much to use, when you should do a water change.
Another thing that you can put in your tank is aquarium salt.
Aquarium salt raises the electrolytes in the tank and it also helps reduce stress.
My name is Michael and today we're talking about how to diagnose an ailment.